[
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Biology is the science of life forms and living ____.",
    "answer": "Processes"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "The living world comprises amazing ____ of organisms.",
    "answer": "Diversity"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "The amazing diversity mentioned is of ____ organisms.",
    "answer": "Living"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Early man perceived difference between living and ____ matter.",
    "answer": "Inanimate"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Early man could easily ____ differences between living and non-living.",
    "answer": "Perceive"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Early man deified inanimate matter like ____.",
    "answer": "Fire"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Along with fire and sea, early man also deified ____. ",
    "answer": "Animals"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Common feature of inanimate and animate forms was ____.",
    "answer": "Fear"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "The sense evoked by animate and inanimate forms was ____.",
    "answer": "Awe"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Description of living beings began much later in ____ history.",
    "answer": "Human"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Description of organisms including ____ began late in history.",
    "answer": "Humans"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "The limited progress was due to ____ view of biology.",
    "answer": "Anthropocentric"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Anthropocentric views caused limited ____ in biology.",
    "answer": "Progress"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Identification, classification and ____ developed out of necessity.",
    "answer": "Nomenclature"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Detailed systems of nomenclature and classification followed ____ description.",
    "answer": "Systematic"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Such studies led to recognition of ____ among organisms.",
    "answer": "Similarities"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Similarities were observed both horizontally and ____.",
    "answer": "Vertically"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Relatedness among organisms led to ____ of biodiversity.",
    "answer": "Conservation"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Realisation of universal relatedness humbled ____.",
    "answer": "Man"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "The perspective used for classification is ____'s.",
    "answer": "Taxonomist"
  },
  {
    "type": "oneword",
    "question": "Classification is of ____ and plants.",
    "answer": "Animals"
  }
]
